Hello everyone, welcome back to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎回到EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
And my name is Katrin and today we are talking about an important holiday the world over.
我是Katrin，今天我们要讨论一个全世界都很重要的节日。
It's very important all over the world, especially in the United States.
这个节日在全世界都很重要，尤其是在美国。
So let's take a look at this holiday in Vocabulary Preview.
那么，我们先在词汇预览中看看这个节日。
Vocabulary Preview.
词汇预览。
So the name of the holiday is Veterans Day.
这个节日的名字是“退伍军人节”。
So veteran.
所以，“退伍军人”。
So what's a veteran?
那么，什么是退伍军人？
A veteran is a person who has participated in a war or in some kind of military situation.
退伍军人是指参加过战争或某种军事行动的人。
Okay.
好的。
So Veterans Day is a day where you commemorate all the people that fought in the different
所以退伍军人节是一个纪念所有在不同战争中战斗过的人的日子。
wars.
战争。
Exactly.
没错。
A veteran doesn't have to be a World War II veteran.
退伍军人不一定非得是二战老兵。
They could be a Civil War veteran or a Vietnam War veteran.
他们可能是内战老兵或越战老兵。
Just a general term.
只是一个通用术语。
Or a Gulf War.
或者海湾战争。
Exactly.
没错。
So that's the day in the United States where everyone honors all the soldiers that participated
所以在美国，这一天是大家向所有参与不同战争并为国家战斗的士兵致敬的日子。
in different wars and they fought for their country.
他们为国家而战。
Alright.
好的。
So why don't we take a look at our dialogue for the first time and we'll be back.
那么，我们先来听一遍对话，稍后再回来。
Do you have any plans for Veterans Day?
退伍军人节你有什么计划吗？
You mean Amistiz Day?
你是说“停战日”吗？
What are you talking about?
你在说什么？
November 11th is Veterans Day.
11月11日是退伍军人节。
What planet are you from?
你是从哪个星球来的？
Well, as you know, on November 11th the Allies signed a peace treaty with the Germans, also
嗯，如你所知，11月11日，协约国与德国签署了和平条约。
known as the Amistiz Treaty.
也被称为《停战条约》。
This marked the end of World War I and many countries around the world commemorated this
这标志着第一次世界大战的结束，世界上许多国家都以不同的名称纪念这个日子。
date under names such as Remembrance Day.
比如“阵亡将士纪念日”。
In Poland, it's their Independence Day.
在波兰，这是他们的独立日。
There's a lot going on around the world on this day.
这一天在世界各地有很多活动。
Wow.
哇。
I didn't know.
我不知道。
Probably because I flunked history in school.
可能是因为我上学时历史课不及格。
Alright so there's a lot of really great vocabulary in this elementary lesson.
好的，这节基础课里有很多很棒的词汇。
So let's take a look at some of these words and phrases in Language Takeaway.
那么，我们来看看“语言要点”中的一些单词和短语。
Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
Alright so the first word that came up after the guy mentioned Veterans Day, the girl mentioned
好的，第一个词是，在男生提到“退伍军人节”后，女生提到了“停战日”。
Armistice Day.
“停战日”。
Armistice.
“停战”。
Okay.
好的。
So what is this Armistice Day?
那么什么是“停战日”？
Armistice means to stop fighting, right?
“停战”意思是停止战斗，对吧？
So it's a time in which people lay down their arms, we say.
所以这是一个人们放下武器的时间，我们这么说。
And it's one that's celebrated in Commonwealth countries like England or Canada and in parts
这个节日在英联邦国家如英国或加拿大以及欧洲部分地区庆祝。
of Europe.
欧洲部分地区。
Okay, very good.
好的，很好。
So Armistice Day, kind of like the equivalent for Commonwealth countries to Veterans Day.
所以“停战日”有点像英联邦国家对应的“退伍军人节”。
Alright and well the girl gave him a bit of a history lesson and mentioned that on November
好的，然后女生给他上了一堂历史课，提到11月11日协约国签署了和平条约。
11th, the Allies signed a peace treaty.
11月11日，协约国签署了和平条约。
So we have two great words here.
这里有两个很好的词。
Allies.
“协约国”。
So Allies is a word that we use in English to indicate people who fought against the
“协约国”是英语中用来指代在二战中对抗德国、意大利和日本的国家。
Germans, Italians and Japanese in World War II.
对抗德国、意大利和日本。
So Allies include Great Britain, America, France for some time.
所以协约国包括英国、美国、法国（一段时间内）。
So these are countries that were, and Russia, they were fighting against the Germans.
还有俄罗斯，这些国家都在对抗德国。
Right.
对。
So in general terms, an ally is a friend, right?
所以一般来说，“盟友”是朋友，对吧？
Exactly.
没错。
So Marco and I are allies.
所以Marco和我是盟友。
If there's a fight, I'm on his side.
如果有冲突，我会站在他这边。
The opposite of enemies.
与敌人相反。
Exactly.
没错。
Very good.
很好。
And well the Allies signed a peace treaty.
然后协约国签署了和平条约。
So what is a peace treaty?
那么什么是和平条约？
A treaty is a document that outlines new rules for a situation.
条约是一份概述新规则的文件。
And a peace treaty is a document that calls for peace.
而和平条约是一份呼吁和平的文件。
It says we will not fight anymore.
它说我们不再战斗了。
We will have peace and this is what this means.
我们将拥有和平，这就是它的含义。
So we have new rules.
所以我们有了新规则。
So it's an agreement.
所以这是一份协议。
It's like a contract.
就像一份合同。
Exactly.
没错。
It's a contract between nations.
这是国家之间的合同。
Okay, very good.
好的，很好。
Alright and as we mentioned, Veterans Day or Armistice Day, we commemorate these events
好的，正如我们提到的，退伍军人节或停战日，我们纪念这些过去发生的事件。
that happened in the past.
纪念这些过去发生的事件。
So to commemorate something.
所以“纪念”某事。
Right.
对。
So in a sense, we are honoring it.
从某种意义上说，我们是在致敬。
So to commemorate is to remember, to honor, to...
所以“纪念”就是记住、致敬……
Remember with respect.
带着敬意记住。
So yeah, to remember with respect.
是的，带着敬意记住。
Exactly.
没错。
There's a positive, respectful tone here.
这里有一种积极、尊重的语气。
It's remembering for a good reason.
这是出于好的理由而记住。
Okay, very good.
好的，很好。
So we've taken a look at these four words.
我们已经看了这四个词。
Why don't we listen to our dialogue again and we'll be back in a bit to look at Fluency
我们再来听一遍对话，稍后回来看看“流利度构建”。
Builder.
“流利度构建”。
Do you have any plans for Veterans Day?
退伍军人节你有什么计划吗？
You mean Armistice Day?
你是说“停战日”吗？
What are you talking about?
你在说什么？
November 11th is Veterans Day.
11月11日是退伍军人节。
What planet are you from?
你是从哪个星球来的？
Well, as you know, on November 11th, the Allies signed a peace treaty with the Germans, also
嗯，如你所知，11月11日，协约国与德国签署了和平条约。
known as the Armistice Treaty.
也被称为《停战条约》。
This marked the end of World War I and many countries around the world commemorated this
这标志着第一次世界大战的结束，世界上许多国家都以不同的名称纪念这个日子。
date under names such as Remembrance Day.
比如“阵亡将士纪念日”。
In Poland, it's their Independence Day.
在波兰，这是他们的独立日。
There's a lot going on around the world on this day.
这一天在世界各地有很多活动。
Wow, I didn't know.
哇，我不知道。
Probably because I flunked history in school.
可能是因为我上学时历史课不及格。
Today's Fluency Builder includes a couple of really interesting phrases that are kind
今天的“流利度构建”包括几个非常有趣的短语，它们有点长。
of longer.
有点长。
So, let's take a look at the first one, which is very, very common in English.
那么，我们先看第一个，这在英语中非常非常常见。
All right.
好的。
So, this first sentence was kind of using a sarcastic tone because he said, what are
所以，第一句话带点讽刺的语气，因为他说：“你在说什么？”
you talking about?
对。
Right.
所以这个男生说：“退伍军人节？”
So, this guy says, Veterans Day?
“哦，你是说停战日？”
Oh, you mean Armistice Day?
“你在说什么？”
What are you talking about?
That means, no, I mean Veterans Day.
这意味着：“不，我是说退伍军人节。”
Right.
对。
So, he wasn't really asking like, what are you talking about?
所以他并不是真的在问“你在说什么？”
He was literally saying with this sentence, are you crazy?
他这句话简直就是在说：你疯了吗？
You're wrong.
你错了。
So, what are you talking about is a way, very sarcastic way to say, listen, I think you're
所以，“你在说什么”是一种非常讽刺的方式，意思是：听着，我觉得你
wrong or you must be a little bit crazy.
错了，或者你一定是有点疯了。
Right.
对。
What are you talking about?
你在说什么？
All right.
好吧。
And then, to end the whole sarcastic sentence there, he said, what planet are you from?
然后，为了结束这句讽刺的话，他说：你是从哪个星球来的？
So, obviously, this is Veterans Day.
所以，很明显，这是退伍军人节。
What planet are you from?
你是从哪个星球来的？
So, you're so wrong.
所以，你错得太离谱了。
How do you not understand what this is?
你怎么会不明白这是什么？
How do you not know this?
你怎么会不知道这个？
Right.
对。
And so, for example, I could say, maybe I'll ask you, Marco, who's the President of the
所以，举个例子，我可以问，Marco，美国总统是谁？
United States?
美国总统是谁？
All right.
好吧。
I can say, well, what planet are you from?
我可以说：你是从哪个星球来的？
It's obviously President Obama.
显然是奥巴马总统。
Oh, duh.
哦，废话。
So, it's like, obviously, everybody knows this.
所以，就好像，显然，每个人都知道这个。
Right.
对。
So, you're saying, how do you not know this already?
所以，你是在说：你怎么会还不知道这个？
So, it's very sarcastic.
所以，这非常讽刺。
What planet are you from?
你是从哪个星球来的？
And finally, the guy is talking about how he doesn't understand what the meaning of
最后，那个人在说他不懂退伍军人节的意义。
Veterans Day is.
退伍军人节的意义。
And after this long explanation, he says, well, I didn't know, probably because I flunked
经过这么长的解释后，他说：嗯，我不知道，可能是因为我上学时历史课不及格。
history in school.
我上学时历史课不及格。
Right.
对。
So, if you flunked history or you flunked any subject in school, it means you didn't
所以，如果你历史课不及格，或者你在学校任何科目不及格，意思是你没通过。
pass.
没通过。
Exactly.
没错。
So, flunk, to flunk is a verb in English and it means to fail a subject.
所以，flunk，to flunk 在英语中是一个动词，意思是某科目不及格。
It means maybe in 100% is perfect, you got 50% or 40% and you have to take the course
意思是，也许满分是100%，你只得了50%或40%，然后你得重修这门课。
again.
重修这门课。
Okay.
好的。
Did you ever flunk an exam in school?
你在学校考试不及格过吗？
No.
没有。
No, really?
没有，真的吗？
You didn't?
你没有？
Never?
从来没有？
No.
没有。
Wow.
哇。
Such a good student.
真是个好学生。
Did you?
你呢？
Maybe.
也许吧。
I did maybe once or twice.
我可能有过一两次。
I was much too self-critical.
我对自己太苛刻了。
All right.
好吧。
Let's listen to this dialogue again and we'll be back in a bit.
我们再听一遍这段对话，一会儿回来。
Do you have any plans for Veterans Day?
退伍军人节你有什么计划吗？
You mean Armistice Day?
你是说停战纪念日？
What are you talking about?
你在说什么？
November 11th is Veterans Day.
11月11日是退伍军人节。
What planet are you from?
你是从哪个星球来的？
Well, as you know, on November 11th, the Allies signed a peace treaty with the Germans, also
嗯，如你所知，11月11日，协约国与德国签署了和平条约，也就是停战条约。
known as the Armistice Treaty.
也就是停战条约。
This marked the end of World War I and many countries around the world commemorated this
这标志着第一次世界大战的结束，世界许多国家都以诸如“阵亡将士纪念日”等名称纪念这一天。
date under names such as Remembrance Day.
这一天。
In Poland, it's their Independence Day.
在波兰，这是他们的独立日。
There's a lot going on around the world on this day.
这一天世界各地有很多活动。
Wow.
哇。
I didn't know.
我不知道。
Probably because I flunked history in school.
可能是因为我上学时历史课不及格。
All right.
好吧。
So Veterans Day, it's a big deal in the United States, right?
所以，退伍军人节在美国是个大事，对吧？
It's a very big deal.
这是件大事。
There's a parade.
有游行。
Yeah, in most cities in the country, there are parades.
是的，全国大多数城市都有游行。
And when I was in school, we had to play music because I was in band.
我上学的时候，我们得演奏音乐，因为我在乐队里。
We used to play music for the veterans and we'd go to the cemetery and play taps.
我们过去常为退伍军人演奏音乐，还会去墓地吹奏《熄灯号》。
No, we didn't play taps.
不，我们没吹《熄灯号》。
It was...
那是……
That's like the funeral song.
那就像葬礼曲。
Yeah, we would play funeral songs and taps for the local veterans who will be respecting
是的，我们会为当地退伍军人演奏葬礼曲和《熄灯号》，以表达对阵亡将士的尊敬和纪念。
and commemorating fallen soldiers.
纪念阵亡将士。
Wow.
哇。
And then talks as well, like on national TV and stuff.
还有演讲，比如在国家电视台之类的。
That's right.
没错。
All right.
好吧。
So it's very interesting, especially the history lesson, the fact that on November, I think
所以这非常有趣，尤其是历史课，事实上在11月，我想它被称为11-11-11，对吧？
it's called 11-11-11, right?
11月11日11点，他们签署了停战条约。
November 11th at 11 o'clock, they signed this armistice treaty.
他们签署了停战条约。
And that was in 1918.
那是在1918年。
So this is World War I.
所以这是第一次世界大战。
We're talking about when the world had never really seen fighting like this before.
我们说的是世界从未见过如此惨烈战斗的时候。
And so everyone was just relieved when what they called the Great War was finally over.
所以当这场被称为“大战”的战争终于结束时，每个人都松了一口气。
It's a very interesting history lesson.
这是一堂非常有趣的历史课。
So I'm sure many people have some opinions on this.
所以我相信很多人对此有自己的看法。
So we would be glad to hear it from you on our website at EnglishPod.com.
我们很乐意在我们的网站 EnglishPod.com 上听到你的意见。
You can also leave questions or comments and we'll see you guys there.
你也可以留下问题或评论，我们会在那里见。
And let us know, do you celebrate this holiday in your country?
请告诉我们，你们国家庆祝这个节日吗？
Yep.
是的。
All right.
好吧。
Until next time.
下次见。
Thanks for watching.
感谢观看。